Guide to the Frank Baker collection of Methodist circuit plans, 1777-1984 and undated RL.00892
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Frank Baker collection of Methodist circuit plans
1777-1984 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Baker, Frank, 1910-1999
RL.00892
8.5 Linear Feet
Approx. 2000 items
Consists predominantly of circuit plans from the Methodist Church (Great Britain) and the earlier churches that merged to form it in 1907 and 1932: the Wesleyan Methodist Church, the Primitive Methodist Church, the United Methodist Free Churches, and the United Methodist Church (Great Britain). These circuit plans, collected by Frank Baker, document the history, growth, and organization of the itinerancy, established by John Wesley in the early years of the church when Methodism began to spread into the rural areas of England. The plans feature detailed schedules of where the itinerant preachers, known as circuit riders, were to appear and preach each week.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Historical note
Frank Baker was a scholar, editor, collector, and Duke University faculty member specializing in the history of English and American Methodist history, and of the life and career of minister John Wesley.
Provenance
The Frank Baker Collection of Methodist Circuit Plans were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1976, 1996.
Collection Overview
The Frank Baker Collection of Methodist Circuit Plans, 1777-1984 and undated, consists predominantly of circuit plans from the Methodist Church (Great Britain) and the earlier churches that merged to form it in 1907 and 1932: the Wesleyan Methodist Church, the Primitive Methodist Church, the United Methodist Free Churches, and the United Methodist Church (Great Britain). These plans document the history, growth, and organization of the itinerancy, established by John Wesley in the early years of the church when Methodism began to spread into the rural areas of England. The circuit plans feature detailed schedules of where the itinerant preachers, known as circuit riders, were to appear and preach each week.
Items in the 19th Century and Overseas Circuits Series were donated in the 1970s and were organized at the item level and encapsulated in the early 1980s. Items were numbered in the order in which they were encapsulated, which bears no relationship to alphabetical order or circuit organization. They are currently boxed in numerical order in three boxes with the following number ranges: Box 1: items 1-240; Box 2, items 241-390; Box 3: items 391-527. Items in the 20th Century Series, numbering around 800 to 1000 items, were donated in the late 1980s and are organized to the folder level.
Related Material
Cirplan: the Bulletin of the Society of Cirplanologists
Rubenstein Library
Frank Baker Collection of Wesleyana and British Methodism, 1536-1996 and undated, Volumes Series, Local Histories Subseries, Circuit Plans, Hull, 1821-1841
Rubenstein Library
Frank Baker Papers, 1641-2002 and undated
Rubenstein Library
Thomas Marriott British Methodist Circuit Plans Collection, 1823-1833
General Commission on Archives and History of the United Methodist Church
Itinerancy (Church polity) -- Methodist Church -- History; Circuit riders -- History; Wesleyan Methodist Church; United Methodist Free Churches; United Methodist Church (Great Britain); Primitive Methodist Church (Great Britain); Methodist Church (Great Britain); Baker, Frank, 1910-1999
- 19th Century Series, 1777-1961
  - Information folder (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Article by Frank Baker, The Circuit Plan, published in Library Notes, no. 49, 1979, Duke University Library.
  - Alford, 1873, July-Oct., Item #440 (Box 1, Folder A)
  - Alford, Boston, Grimsby (Reform), 1852 Nov.-1853 Feb., Item #290 (Box 1)
  - Alston (P), 1845 Aug.-Oct., Item #409 (Box 1)
  - Alston, 1883 Feb.-Apr., Item #437 (Box 1)
  - Alston, 1883 Aug.-Oct., Item #488 (Box 1)
  - Appleby, 1850 May-July, Item #245 (Box 1)
  - Appleby and Kirkby Stephen, 1873 Nov.-1874 Feb., Item #465 (Box 1)
  - Bacup, 1876 Aug.-Oct., Item #448 (Box 1, Folder B1)
  - Bardney, 1911 July-Oct., Item #350 (Box 1)
  - Barnard Castle (Prayer Leaders):
    - 1839 Apr.-Oct., Item #200 (Box 1)
    - 1840 May-Oct., Item #201 (Box 1)
    - 1845 July-Dec., Item #39 (Box 1)
  - Barnsley (P), 1841 Jan.-Apr., Item #253 (Box 1)
  - Barnsley:
    - 1844 Jan.-Apr., Item #72 (Box 1)
    - 1844 Apr.-July, Item #146 (Box 1)
    - 1849 Oct.-1850 Jan., Item #167 (Box 1)
  - Barnsley (Reform), 1933 Aug.-Oct., Item #197 (Box 1)
  - Barnsley Methodist Council Agenda, 1932 May 6th, Item #50 (Box 1)
  - Barnsley, Westgate, etc., 1934 Apr.-July, Item #9 (Box 1)
  - Birmingham Central Mission 1894 July-Sept., Item #223 (Box 1)
  - Bolton (1. F.) (Prayer Meetings and their sections), 1828 Nov.-1829 Apr., Item #94 (Box 1, Folder B2)
  - Bolton (2. F.), 1828 Nov.-1829 Apr., Item #89 (Box 1)
  - Bolton (1. S.), 1820 Dec.-1821 May, Item #70 (Box 1)
  - Bolton (2. S.), 1820 Dec.-1821 May, Item #88 (Box 1)
  - Bolton (1. F. + 2. F.), 1829 Sept.-1830 Feb., Item #481 (Box 1)
  - Bolton (2. S.), 1832 Apr.-July, Item #90 (Box 1)
  - Bolton (1. F. + 2. F.), 1833 Apr.-July, Item #496 (Box 1)
  - Bolton (2. S.), 1834 Oct.-1835 Jan., Item #86 (Box 1)
  - Bolton (1. S.), 1835 May-Aug., Item #103 (Box 1)
  - Bolton (II. F.), 1837 Apr.-June, Item #82 (Box 1)
  - Bolton (I. F. + II. F.), 1838 Apr.-July, Item #499 (Box 1)
  - Bolton:
    - 1839 Dec.-1840 Mar., Item #87 (Box 1)
    - 1843 Oct.-1844 Jan., Item #104 (Box 1)
    - 1844 Feb.-May, Item #79 (Box 1)
    - 1844 Dec.-1845 Mar., Item #99 (Box 1)
    - 1846 Jan.-Apr., Item #102 (Box 1)
  - Bolton (Regular Services): (Folder B3)
    - 1843 July-Oct., Item #150 (Box 1)
    - 1844 May-Oct., Item #215 (Box 1)
    - 1845 May-Oct., Item #219 (Box 1)
    - 1846 May-Oct., Item #220 (Box 1)
    - 1847 Oct.-1848 Apr., Item #381 (Box 1)
    - 1850 July-Oct., Item #382 (Box 1)
    - 1851 Mar.-June, Item #383 (Box 1)
    - 1851 Nov.-1852 Feb., Item #384 (Box 1)
    - 1853 Mar.-June, Item #385 (Box 1)
    - 1855 Feb.-Apr., Item #386 (Box 1)
    - 1856 Feb.-Apr., Item #387 (Box 1)
    - 1856 Nov.-1857 Jan., Item #388 (Box 1)
  - Bolton North:
    - 1861 July-Oct., Item #450 (Box 1)
    - 1862 July-Oct., Item #434 (Box 1)
    - 1893 Aug.-Oct., Item #490 (Box 1)
  - Bolton South, 1862 Feb.-May, Item #442 (Box 1)
  - Bolton, Bridge Street: (Folder B4)
    - 1870 Nov.-1871 Jan., Item #466 (Box 1)
    - 1871 May-July, Item #467 (Box 1)
    - 1873 Nov.-1874 Jan., Item #468 (Box 1)
    - 1874 Nov.-1875 Jan., Item #469 (Box 1)
    - 1875 Aug.-Oct., Item #470 (Box 1)
    - 1876 Feb.-Apr., Item #471 (Box 1)
    - 1877 May-July, Item #472 (Box 1)
    - 1879 May-July, Item #473 (Box 1)
    - 1880 Feb.-Apr., Item #474 (Box 1)
    - 1881 Jan.-Apr., Item #475 (Box 1)
    - 1882 July-Oct., Item #476 (Box 1)
    - 1883 Jan.-Apr., Item #477 (Box 1)
  - B51879 Nov.-1880 Jan., Item #438 (Box 1)
  - Boston:
    - 1820 Nov.-1821 Jan., Item #73 (Box 1)
    - 1863 Jan.-Apr., Item #483 (Box 1)
    - 1881 July-Oct., Item #237 (Box 1)
    - 1895 May-July, Item #405 (Box 1)
  - Boston (United Methodist Free Churches), 1883 Jan.-Apr., Item #282 (Box 1)
  - Bradford (P), 1841 Jan.-Mar., Item #336 (Box 1, Folder B5)
  - Bradford, Kirkgate, 1883 Nov.-1884 Feb., Item #127 (Box 1)
  - Bramley, 1865 Oct.-Dec., Item #399 (Box 1)
  - Bridlington (P), 1866 July-Oct., Item #418 (Box 1)
  - Brigg and Alkbro' (P):
    - 1839 July-Oct., Item #330 (Box 1)
    - 1840 Jan.-Apr., Item #366 (Box 1)
    - 1840 July-Oct., Item #145 (Box 1)
    - 1840 Oct.-1841 Jan., Item #124 (Box 1)
    - 1841 Jan.-Apr., Item #131 (Box 1)
    - (Ms. Notes),, Item #137 (Box 1)
    - 1841 May-July, Item #144 (Box 1)
    - (Ms. Notes) (Box 1)
  - Brighton, 1853 Feb.-Apr., Item #162 (Box 1)
  - Brighton, 1854 Oct.-1855 Jan., Item #252 (Box 1)
  - Bristol, 1838 July-Aug., Item #363 (Box 1)
  - Brompton (P), 1841 Jan.-Apr., Item #176 (Box 1)
  - Brough and Penrith, 1822 Feb.-Apr., Item #105 (Box 1)
  - Burslem, 1807 Feb.-July, Item #159 (Box 1)
  - Burslem, 1807 Aug.-1808 Jan., Item #225 (Box 1)
  - Bury (P), 1894 July-Oct., Item #361 (Box 1)
  - Caistor and Laceby, 1894 July-Oct., Item #489 (Box 1, Folder C)
  - Caistor and Laceby, 1895 July-Oct., Item #486 (Box 1)
  - Camborne, 1834 July-Oct., Item #26 (Box 1)
  - Camelford (Bible Christian), 1903 Nov.-1904 Jan., Item #492 (Box 1)
  - Carmarthen and Llanelly, 1868 May-Aug., Item #101 (Box 1)
  - Castle Donington, 1884 May-July, Item #494 (Box 1)
  - Chatteris, 1854 Oct.-1855 Feb., Item #248 (Box 1)
  - Chertsey and Walton-on-Thames, 1873 Apr.-July, Item #278 (Box 1)
  - Chertsey and Walton-on-Thames, 1873 Oct.-1874 Jan., Item #495 (Box 1)
  - Chesterfield, 1818 May-Nov., Item #322 (Box 1)
  - Clitheroe, 1878 Aug.-Oct., Item #412 (Box 1)
  - Cobham, 1873 Aug.-Oct., Item #213 (Box 1)
  - Congleton, 1837 Oct.-1838 Jan., Item #257 (Box 1)
  - Coningsby, 1857 May-Aug., Item #115 (Box 1)
  - Cottenham, 1881 Nov.-1882 Feb., Item #204 (Box 1)
  - Danby, 1865 May-Oct., Item #147 (Box 1, Folder D)
  - Darlington:
    - 1836 May-Oct., Item #183 (Box 1)
    - 1837 Nov.-1838 May, Item #324 (Box 1)
    - 1838 Dec.-1839 Mar., Item #136 (Box 1)
    - 1840 Apr.-Aug., Item #133 (Box 1)
    - 1842 Feb.-May, Item #135 (Box 1)
    - 1844 Oct.-1845 Feb., Item #152 (Box 1)
    - 1846 Apr.-Aug., Item #148 (Box 1)
  - Denby Dale, 1885 Feb.-May, Item #446 (Box 1)
  - Deptford, 1819 May-Oct., Item #241 (Box 1)
  - Derby (Arminian), 1832 July-Oct., Item #4 (Box 1)
  - Devonport, 1960 Apr.-June, Item #30 (Box 1)
  - Doncaster, 1831 Nov.-1832 Jan., Item #238 (Box 1)
  - Doncaster (P), 1840 Nov.-1841 Jan., Item #335 (Box 1)
  - Downham, 1842 Dec.-1843 May, Item #338 (Box 1)
  - Durham, 1858 Feb.-May, Item #240 (Box 1)
  - Durham (Methodist New Connexion), 1859 Jan-Apr., Item #195 (Box 1)
  - Easingwold: (Folder E - Gra)
    - 1826 Nov.-1827 Apr., Item #68 (Box 1)
    - 1842 Dec.-1843 Mar., Item #212 (Box 1)
    - 1848 Oct.-1849 Apr., Item #258 (Box 1)
    - 1851 May-Oct., Item #232 (Box 1)
    - 1866 May-Oct., Item #480 (Box 1)
  - Edinburgh, 1832 Aug.-Oct., Item #25 (Box 1)
  - Epworth:
    - 1814 Jan.-June, Item #21 (Box 1)
    - 1827 Nov.-1828 Apr., Item #77 (Box 1)
    - 1842 May-Oct., Item #262 (Box 1)
  - Epworth (P), 1835 Nov.-1836 Jan., Item #210 (Box 1)
  - Filey, 1961 Jan.-Apr., Item #31 (Box 1)
  - Folkestone, 1881 Nov.-1882 Jan., Item #216 (Box 1)
  - Gainsborough, 1950 Oct.-1951 Jan., Item #71 (Box 1)
  - Gateshead, 1858 May-July, Item #493 (Box 1)
  - Gateshead, 1866 Aug.-Oct., Item #487 (Box 1)
  - Grantham, 1865 May-July, Item #478 (Box 1)
  - Grimsby: (Folder Gri - Hav)
    - 1811 Nov.-1812 Apr., Item #53 (Box 1)
    - 1816 July-Dec., Item #113 (Box 1)
    - 1818 June-Dec., Item #184 (Box 1)
    - 1818 Dec.-1819 June, Item #179 (Box 1)
    - 1819 Dec.-1820 June, Item #187 (Box 1)
    - 1820 Dec.-1821 June, Item #80 (Box 1)
    - 1821 July-Dec., Item #44 (Box 1)
    - 1822 July-Dec., Item #46 (Box 1)
    - 1859 Sept.-Dec., Item #441 (Box 1)
    - 1860 May-Aug., Item #464 (Box 1)
  - Grimsby, Duncombe St., 1896 Apr.-July, Item #10 (Box 1)
  - Grimsby, Duncombe St., 1912 Apr.-July, Item #11 (Box 1)
  - Halifax (P):
    - 1829 Dec.-1830 Mar., Item #188 (Box 1)
    - 1830 Apr.-June, Item #191 (Box 1)
    - 1841 Jan.-Apr., Item #279 (Box 1)
  - Halifax, South Parade, 1880 May-Aug., Item #246 (Box 1)
  - Halifax, Wesley, 1880 May-July, Item #504 (Box 1)
  - Haslingden, 1844 May-Oct., Item #62 (Box 1)
  - Hastings, 1841 Apr.-July, Item #209 (Box 1)
  - Haverfordwest, 1832 May-Oct., Item #163 (Box 1)
  - Hertford and Bishop's Stortford, 1873 Nov.-1874 Jan., Item #431 (Box 1, Folder H1)
  - Hexham, 1870 Aug.-Oct., Item #242 (Box 1)
  - Holbeach, 1896 Jan-Apr., Item #149 (Box 1)
  - Holt, 1883 Oct.-1884 Jan., Item #203 (Box 1)
  - Horncastle (P):
    - 1877 Jan.-Apr., Item #505 (Box 1)
    - 1902 Dec.-1903 Mar., Item #452 (Box 1)
    - 1906 July-Sept., Item #453 (Box 1)
    - 1907 Jan.-Mar., Item #454 (Box 1)
    - 1908 Oct.-Dec., Item #455 (Box 1)
    - 1911 Jan.-Mar., Item #456 (Box 1)
    - 1913 Apr.-June, Item #457 (Box 1)
    - 1914 Jan.-Mar., Item #458 (Box 1)
    - 1924 Oct.-Dec., Item #459 (Box 1)
    - 1925 Jan.-Mar., Item #460 (Box 1)
    - 1926 Apr.-June, Item #461 (Box 1)
    - 1926 Oct.-Dec., Item #462 (Box 1)
    - 1928 Oct.-Dec., Item #463 (Box 1)
  - Horncastle, 1903 Apr.-July, Item #12 (Box 1)
  - Horncastle, 1951 Jan.-Apr., Item #398 (Box 1)
  - Houghton-Le-Spring: (Folder H2)
    - 1875 Feb.-Apr., Item #425 (Box 1)
    - 1875 Aug.-Oct., Item #426 (Box 1)
    - 1875 Nov.-1876 Jan., Item #427 (Box 1)
    - 1876 Feb.-Apr., Item #428 (Box 1)
    - 1876 May-June, Item #429 (Box 1)
    - 1891 Aug.-Oct., Item #430 (Box 1)
  - Howden, 1873 May-July, Item #445 (Box 1)
  - Huddersfield, 1829 Nov.-1830 Apr., Item #151 (Box 1)
  - Huddersfield (Weeknights), 1831 Sept.-Dec., Item #3 (Box 1)
  - Huddersfield:
    - 1832 Mar.-Aug., Item #340 (Box 1)
    - 1870? Aug.-Oct., Item #141 (Box 1)
    - 1880? Feb.-Apr., Item #171 (Box 1)
    - 1880 May-July, Items #185 and #192 (Box 1)
    - 1880 Aug.-Oct., Item #157 (Box 1)
    - 1884 Aug.-Oct., Item #156 (Box 1)
  - Huddersfield (P), 1830 July-Sept., Item #169 (Box 1)
  - Huddersfield (P), 1840 Nov.-1841 Jan., Item #276 (Box 1)
  - Hull, 1808 May-Oct., Item #43 (Box 1, Folder H3)
  - Hull (P) (Prayer Meetings), 1828 Feb.-Apr., Item #42 (Box 1)
  - Hull (P):
    - 1825 Jan.-Apr., Item #83 (Box 1)
    - 1838 Jan.-Apr., Item #293 (Box 1)
    - 1840 Aug.-Oct., Item #196 (Box 1)
    - 1841 May-July, Item #158 (Box 1)
    - 1841 Jan.-Apr., Item #352 (Box 1)
    - 1886 Oct.-1887 Jan., Item #407 (Box 1)
  - Hull (P) (District Meeting), 1870 May, Item #182 (Box 1)
  - Hull, East, 1858 Aug.-1859 Jan., Item #509 (Box 1)
  - Hull (P), Fourth, 1881 Jan.-Apr., Item #424 (Box 1)
  - Hull (P), Fourth, 1883 Apr.-July, Item #13 (Box 1)
  - Hull, Lambert St. 1937 Apr.-June, Item #76 (Box 1)
  - Hull (P), Spring Bank, 1876 July-Oct., Item #45 (Box 1)
  - Hull, Waltham St., 1954 Oct.-Dec., Item #186 (Box 1)
  - Hull, Waltham St. (Quarterly Meeting), 1885 Mar., 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Hull, Plan of the Religious Services in Connexion with the Wesleyan Methodist Conference, 1848 (Box 1, Folder H4)
  - Isle of Wight, 1844 Jan.-Apr., Item #229 (Box 1, Folder I-K)
  - Isle of Wight (Bible Christian), 1857 May-Aug., Item #6 (Box 1)
  - Keighly (P):
    - 1841 Jan.-Apr., Item #329 (Box 1)
    - 1849 July-Oct., Item #439 (Box 1)
    - 1858 Apr.-July, Item #423 (Box 1)
    - 1863 Oct.-1864 Jan., Item #403 (Box 1)
    - 1866 Apr.-July, Item #389 (Box 1)
  - Keighley (P), Second, 1912 Apr.-June, Item #346 (Box 1)
  - Kentish Missions (P)
    - 1841 Oct.-1842 Jan., Item #91 (Box 1)
    - 1842 Jan.-Apr., Item #109 (Box 1)
    - 1842 May-July, Item #24 (Box 1)
  - Keyingham (P), 1840 Nov.-1841 Jan., Item #269 (Box 1)
  - Kilkhampton, 1871 Nov.-1872 Feb., Item #247 (Box 1)
  - Kilkhampton, 1872 Feb.-May, Item #139 (Box 1)
  - Kilkhampton (United Methodist), 1911 May-July, Item #498 (Box 1)
  - Kirkoswald, 1883 Aug.-Nov., Item #447 (Box 1)
  - Kirkoswald, 1899 July-Oct., Item #410 (Box 1)
  - Knaresborough, 1881 Aug.-Oct., Item #374 (Box 1)
  - Knaresborough, 1876 Nov.-1877 Jan., Item #411 (Box 1)
  - Knowl-Wood (P), 1840 Oct.-1841 Jan., Item #294 (Box 1)
  - Lancaster, 1862 Nov.-1863 Jan., Item #138 (Box 1, Folder L1)
  - Leicester (P), 1829 July-Oct., Item #173 (Box 1)
  - Leeds (Ms., facsim.), 1777 May-July, Item #5 (Box 1)
  - Leeds, 1818 Nov.-1819 Apr., Item #108 (Box 1)
  - Leeds (P), 1841 Jan-Apr., Item #268 (Box 1)
  - Leeds (P), South, 1841 Jan-Apr., Item #287 (Box 1)
  - Leeds, Armley, 1884 Jan-Apr., Item #226 (Box 1)
  - Leeds, Wesley, 1874 Feb.-Apr., Item #416 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln, 1844 Feb.-July, Item #497 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln, Wesley, 1884 May-July, Item #349 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln, Wesley, 1898 Oct.-1899 Jan., Item #14 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln (Methodist Free Churches), 1900 Nov.-1901 Jan., Item #406 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln (Methodist Free Churches), 1904 Feb.-Apr., Item #401 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln (P):
    - 1836 July-Oct., Item #74 (Box 1)
    - 1836 Oct.-1837 Jan., Item #57 (Box 1)
    - 1837 Jan.-Apr., Item #56 (Box 1)
    - 1837 Apr.-July, Item #58 (Box 1)
    - 1837 July-Oct., Item #59 (Box 1)
  - Lindley (Methodist New Connexion), 1879 Nov.-1880 Feb., Item #380 (Box 1)
  - Liverpool: (Folder L2)
    - 1809 July-Oct., Item #230 (Box 1)
    - 1809 Oct.-1810 Jan., Item #358 (Box 1)
    - 1810 Jan.-Apr., Item #85 (Box 1)
    - 1810 Apr.-July, Item #356 (Box 1)
    - 1810 July-Oct., Item #343 (Box 1)
    - 1810 Oct.-1811 Jan., Item #194 (Box 1)
    - 1811 Jan.-Apr., Item #208 (Box 1)
    - 1811 Apr.-July, Item #168 (Box 1)
    - 1811 July-Oct., Item #172 (Box 1)
  - Liverpool, North, 1832 May-Aug., Item #261 (Box 1)
  - Liverpool, North, 1854 June-Sept., Item #373 (Box 1)
  - Liverpool, Brunswick, 1864 May-Aug., Item #413 (Box 1)
  - Liverpool, South, 1854 June-Sept., Item #375 (Box 1)
  - Liverpool, Pitt. St., 1864 Apr.-June, Item #360 (Box 1)
  - Liverpool, Pitt. St., 1867 Apr.-June, Item #370 (Box 1)
  - Liverpool, South, Pitt. St., 1861 Sept.-Dec., Item #377 (Box 1)
  - Liverpool, Cramner:
    - 1867 Feb.-Apr., Item #369 (Box 1)
    - 1876 Oct.-1877 Jan., Item #368 (Box 1)
    - 1885 Jan.-Mar., Item #379 (Box 1)
  - [Liverpool], Waterloo, 1864 Apr.-June, Item #174 (Box 1)
  - Liverpool, Wesley, 1864 Apr.-June, Item #422 (Box 1)
  - Liverpool, Wesley, 1867 Apr.-June, Item #376 (Box 1)
  - Liverpool (Conference Plan), 1832 July-Aug., Item #359 (Box 1)
  - London, 1796 June-Sept., Item #243 (Box 1, Folder L3)
  - London, 1803 Oct.-Dec., Item #289, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - London, East:
    - 1819 Feb.-June, Item #143 (Box 1)
  - London, North, 1827 Oct.-1828 Feb., Item #391 (Box 1)
  - London, Second, 1846 Jan.-Mar., Item #207 (Box 1)
  - London, Second, 1848 Jan.-Mar., Item #181 (Box 1)
  - London, Fifth, 1838 May-July, Item #206 (Box 1)
  - London, Fourth and Fifth, etc., 1852 Apr.-June, Item #347 (Box 1)
  - London, Islington, 1864 July-Oct. Item #362 (Box 1)
  - London (P) London Branch of Hull Circuit, 1838 Dec.-1839 Apr., Item #432 (Box 1)
  - London (P) London Mission of Hull Circuit, 1841 Aug.-Oct., Item #503 (Box 1)
  - London, Highgate, 1955 Apr.-June, Item #15 (Box 1)
  - Louth (P):
    - 1837 Oct.-1838 Jan., Item #291 (Box 1)
    - 1838 Apr.-July, Item #292 (Box 1)
    - 1838 July-Oct., Item #479, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - London and Southwark circuits, photocopies, 1811 and 1829-1867
    Photocopies purchased from the collection of John Ellis, Wesley Society, London. Housed in a separate envelope inside folder L3.
    - London, Second, 1848 Apr.-June; 1856 Oct.-Dec.; 1857 Apr.-June, 1858 Oct.-Dec.; 1860 Jan.-Mar.; and 1864 Jan.-Apr. (Box 1)
    - London, Conference, 1829 July-Aug.; 1850 (Box 1)
    - London, Third and Eighth, 1852 Jan.-Apr. (Box 1)
    - London, Kentish Town,1867 July-Sept. (Box 1)
    - Southwark Prayer Meetings, 1811 Aug. 11 (Box 1)
  - London, Second (United Methodist Free Churches), 1860 (Box 1, Folder L4)
  - Maidenhead (P), 1913 Oct.-Dec., Item #251 (Box 3, Folder M1)
  - Malton (P):
    - 1833 June-Sept., Item #75 (Box 3)
    - 1834 Jan.-Mar., Item #129 (Box 3)
    - 1841 Jan.-Apr., Item #263 (Box 3)
  - Manchester:
    - 1799 July-Oct., Item #165 (Box 3)
    - 1799 Oct.-1800 Feb., Item #20 (Box 3)
    - 1802 Feb.-June, Item #? (Box 3)
    - 1808 Aug.-Oct., Item #341 (Box 3)
    - 1802 June-Nov., Item #485 (Box 3)
  - Manchester (Ms. yearly plan of Jabez Bunting), 1805-1806, Item #255 (Box 3)
  - Manchester:
    - 1806 Sept.-1807 Mar., Item #97 (Box 3)
    - 1807 Mar.-July, Item #270 (Box 3)
    - 1807 July-Oct., Item #284 (Box 3)
    - 1809 Feb.-Apr., Item #211 (Box 3)
    - 1810 Aug.-Oct., Item #54 (Box 3)
    - 1818 Jan.-Mar., Item #78 (Box 3)
    - 1818 Apr.-June, Item #47 (Box 3)
  - Manchester, South:
    - 1824 Oct.-1825 Jan., Item #392 (Box 3)
    - 1825 Nov.-1829 Feb., Item #393 (Box 3)
    - 1826 Mar.-May, Item #394 (Box 3)
    - 1826 June-Aug., Item #395 (Box 3)
    - 1826 Sept.-1827 Jan., Item #396 (Box 3)
    - 1827 Dec.-1828 Apr., Item #397 (Box 3)
  - Manchester, North, (Weeknights), 1826 Apr.-Sept., Item #365 (Box 3, Folder M2)
  - Manchester, North, (Weeknights), 1826 Sept.-1827 Jan., Item #364 (Box 3)
  - Manchester, First, 1833 Oct.-1834 Jan., Item #128 (Box 3)
  - Manchester, First, 1859 Mar.-June, Item #114 (Box 3)
  - Manchester, Second, 1860 July-Sept., Item #332 (Box 3)
  - Manchester, Third:
    - 1828 July-Oct., Item #323 (Box 3)
    - 1829 Feb.-May, Item #326 (Box 3)
    - 1845 Mar.-June, Item #355 (Box 3)
    - 1846 July-Sept., Item #390 (Box 3)
    - 1858 Sept.-1859 Jan., Item #121 (Box 3)
  - Manchester, Fourth, 1859 Aug.-Oct., Item #116 (Box 3, Folder M3)
  - Manchester, Fifth, 1859 Apr.-June, Item #339 (Box 3)
  - Manchester, Sixth, 1860 Oct.-Dec., Item #66 (Box 3)
  - Manchester, Sixth, 1864 Feb.-Apr., Item #234 (Box 3)
  - Manchester, Oxford St., 1864 Jan.-Mar., Item #227 (Box 3)
  - Manchester, Radnor St., 1883 Oct.-Dec., Item #93 (Box 3)
  - Manchester (P), 1846 Oct.-1847 Jan., Item #402 (Box 3)
  - Manchester London Rd. (Sunday School), 1831-1832, Item #120 (Box 3)
  - Manchester, South (Evening Prayer), 1824 Sept.-Jan., Item #193 (Box 3)
  - Mansfield: (Folder M4)
    - 1854 July-Nov., Item #353 (Box 3)
    - 1858 Mar.-June, Item #451 (Box 3)
    - 1859 Feb.-May, Item #296 (Box 3)
    - 1860 Feb.-Apr., Item #297 (Box 3)
    - 1860 May-July, Item #298 (Box 3)
    - 1860 Aug.-Oct., Item #299 (Box 3)
    - 1860 Nov.-1861 Jan., Item #300 (Box 3)
    - 1861 Feb.-Apr., Item #301 (Box 3)
    - 1861 May-July, Item #302 (Box 3)
    - 1863 May-July, Item #303 (Box 3)
    - 1863 Nov.-1864 Jan., Item #304 (Box 3)
    - 1864 Aug.-Oct., Item #305 (Box 3)
    - 1864 Nov.-1865 Jan., Item #306 (Box 3)
    - 1865 Feb.-Apr., Item #307 (Box 3)
    - 1865 May-July, Item #308 (Box 3)
    - 1865 Aug.-Oct., Item #309 (Box 3)
    - 1865 Nov.-1866 Jan., Item #310 (Box 3)
    - 1866 Aug.-Oct., Item #311 (Box 3, Folder M5)
    - 1868 Nov.-1869 Jan., Item #312 (Box 3)
    - 1869 Nov.-1870 Jan., Item #313 (Box 3)
    - 1870 Feb.-Apr., Item #314 (Box 3)
    - 1870 May-July, Item #315 (Box 3)
    - 1870 Aug.-Oct., Item #316 (Box 3)
    - 1870 Nov.-1871 Jan., Item #317 (Box 3)
    - 1871 Feb.-Apr., Item #318 (Box 3)
    - 1871 May-July, Item #319 (Box 3)
    - 1871 Aug.-Oct., Item #320 (Box 3)
    - 1873 Feb.-Apr., Item #348 (Box 3)
    - 1873 May-July, Item #321 (Box 3)
    - 1874 May-July, Item #337 (Box 3)
    - 1877 May-July, Item #378 (Box 3)
  - Mansfield (P), 1848 Oct.-1849 Jan., Item #40 (Box 3)
  - Middleham and Tanfield (P), 1815 May-Oct., Item #41 (Box 3)
  - Middleham (P):
    - 1841 Jan.-Apr., Item #189 (Box 3)
    - 1844 Aug.-Oct., Item #119 (Box 3)
    - 1849 Nov.-1850 Jan., Item #142 (Box 3)
  - Nelson, 1896 Aug.-Oct., Item #275 (Box 3, Folder N-O)
  - Newscastle, 1802 Apr.-June, Item #32 (Box 3)
  - Newscastle, 1816 Aug.-Oct., Item #63 (Box 3)
  - North Hill, 1959 July-Oct., Item #16 (Box 3)
  - North Shields, 1843 May-Oct., Item #281 (Box 3)
  - Norwich, 1810 Nov.-1811 Apr., Item #8 (Box 3)
  - Norwich (United Methodist Free Church), 1899 Feb.-Apr., Item #371 (Box 3)
  - Norwich (United Methodist):
    - 1908 Nov.-1909 Jan., Item #273 (Box 3)
    - 1909 May-July, Item #357 (Box 3)
    - 1910 Aug.-Oct., Item #408 (Box 3)
    - 1911 Jan.-Apr., Item #420 (Box 3)
    - 1911 Apr.-July, Item #421 (Box 3)
    - 1911 Nov.-1912 Jan., Item #372 (Box 3)
  - Nottingham, Wesley:
    - 1883 Jan.-Apr., Item #110 (Box 3)
    - 1883 Apr.-July, Item #84 (Box 3)
    - 1883 July-Oct., Item #111 (Box 3)
    - 1883 Oct.-1884 Jan., Item #118 (Box 3)
    - 1884 Jan.-Apr., Item #117 (Box 3)
    - 1884 July-Oct., Item #100 (Box 3)
  - Nottingham, Halifax Place, 1884 Feb.-Apr., Item #17 (Box 3)